<resources>

    <!-- Name of the app -->
    <string name="app_name">Gorgo Tour Guide</string>

    <!-- Name of the fragment dedicated to the general information about the town -->
    <string name="general_info_fragment">The Town</string>

    <!-- Name of the fragment dedicated to the things too see in town  -->
    <string name="places_to_see_fragment">Things to see</string>

    <!-- Name of the fragment dedicated to the things to do in town -->
    <string name="events_in_gorgonzola_fragment">Things to do</string>

    <!-- Name of the fragment dedicated to the directions to get to the town -->
    <string name="flora_of_naviglio_della_martesana_fragment">Directions</string>

    <!-- General text for the content description of the images -->
    <string name="a_view_of_gorgonzola">a view of Gorgonzola</string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about basic info about the town -->
    <string name="gorgonzola">Gorgonzola</string>

    <!-- Text of the basic description about the town -->
    <string name="gorgonzola_description">
        Gorgonzola is a town in the Metropolitan City of Milan, in Lombardy.
        It has around 20500 inhabitants called gorgonzolesi.\nGorgonzoeula
        (IPA: [ɡurɡũˈdzøːla]) is the name of the town in the dialect spoken
        around Milan. Sometimes the town is also called GorgoTown by some,
        in an affectionate and informal fashion.\nBesides the
        characteristic city centre, the territory of Gorgonzola includes the
        hamlets of Frazione Riva, Località Produttiva, Cascina Mugnaga,
        Cascina Vergani, Cascina Nuova e Cascina Antonietta.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about basic geographical info about the town -->
    <string name="geography">Geography</string>

    <!-- Text of the basic geographical description of the town -->
    <string name="geographical_info">
        Gorgonzola is located at 133 m above sea level, 13 Km North &#8211; East of Milan
        in the Martesana territory, once called Martesana county.\nThe Naviglio della
        Martesana, an artificial canal, and the torrent Molgora flow through its flat
        territory.\nThe Pre &#8211; Alps of Bergamo and Lecco and Valtellina are not
        faraway to the North.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about gorgonzola cheese -->
    <string name="cheese">Gorgonzola Cheese</string>

    <!-- Text about gorgonzola cheese -->
    <string name="gorgonzola_cheese_info">
        According to most Gorgonzola is the birthplace of the blue cheese, for sure it
        had been the main centre of its production and trade for many centuries.\nOriginally
        called Stracchino di Gorgonzola, and then also Stracchino verde, gorgonzola cheese
        was produced with the Autumn milk of the weary (stracch in dialect) cows during
        the transhumance from the summer mountain pastures.\nGradually its production
        extended to an area ranging from Piedmont and Lombardy and  which is now defined and
        protected by the PDO mark and the \"Consorzio per la Tutela del Formaggio Gorgonzola DOP\",
        which has also set the processing procedure to obtain the famous blue cheese.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about Parco Agricolo Sud Milano -->
    <string name="parco_agricolo">Parco Agricolo Sud Milano</string>

    <!-- Text about Parco Agricolo Sud Milano -->
    <string name="parco_agricolo_info">
        Gorgonzola is the most North Eastern town belonging to the Parco Agricolo
        Sud Milano, which includes the land of the towns and villages of the Southern
        half of the metropolitan belt surrounding Milan.\nHere agriculture is the
        main activity supporting the protection of the environment and the landscape,
        even if there are also untouched and protected areas, giving the park a high
        plant and animal biodiversity.\nTourism is of a rural and naturalistic kind.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about Gorgonzola in letterature -->
    <string name="literature_curiosity">Literature Curiosity</string>

    <!-- Text of the literature curiosity about Gorgonzola -->
    <string name="literature_curiosity_text">
        In The Bethrothed by Alessandro Manzoni, chapter XVI, it is told that Renzo,
        fleeing from Milan where he was involved in a riot and risked to be arrested,
        headed to Bergamo, in the Republic of Venice, and stopped for dinner in an inn
        in Gorgonzola.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about the twin towns of Gorgonzola -->
    <string name="twin_towns">Twin Towns</string>

    <!-- Text about the twin towns of Gorgonzola -->
    <string name="twin_towns_info">
        Ambert in Auvergne, France, since 2003.\nBoth cities are located almost at the
        same latitude, but most of all both are known for their own blue cheese,
        Fourme d\'Ambert and Gorgonzola.\nAnnweiler am Trifels, Germany, since
        September 2008.\nAnnweiler is a town in the Südliche Weinstraße district,
        in Rhineland-Palatinate, Germany.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about the naviglio martesana -->
    <string name="naviglio">Naviglio della Martesana</string>

    <!-- Text about the naviglio martesana -->
    <string name="naviglio_info">
        The Naviglio della Martesana is a distinctive feature of identity of the
        territory it passes through.\nIt is a 38 Km long artificial canal, that receives
        the waters from the River Adda in Concesa, a hamlet of Trezzo d\'Adda, it crosses
        the Martesana territory and arrives as far as Milan, where it integrates into its
        now largely underground water system.\nIts construction began under the Duke of
        Milan Francesco Sforza in 1457, it was navigable from 1482 and completed in 1496
        under Ludovico il Moro, although a few important adjustments were made
        afterward.\nAt those times the Martesana territory was important not only for the
        agricultural activity, but also for its strategic position, close to the border
        with the Republic of Venice.\nThe Naviglio has been important to move the millstones,
        presses of crushers, spinning machines and paper mills, to connect Milan to the
        River Adda and the Lake of Como, to move people, food supplies and goods
        back and forth.\nWith time it attracted the noble families who established their
        country residences next to it.\nThe boats covered the entire journey from
        Trezzo d\'Adda in 7 and a half hours, from Milan in 12 hours driven by two
        horses.\The naviglio is no longer navigable since 1958, while remaining very
        important both in collecting, regulating rainwater and for irrigation purposes.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about the sanctuary in Gorgonzola -->
    <string name="sanctuary">Sanctuary of Our Lady of Help</string>

    <!-- Text about the twin towns of Gorgonzola -->
    <string name="sanctuary_info">
        This little one nave church was once dedicated to Saint Peter and was part of
        an ancient Umiliati\'s convent, perhaps it was its chapel.\nIts foundation dates
        back to the XII century.\nA part of the convent is still visible in the
        beautiful Corte dei Chiosi.\nIn the XVII century Francesco Maria Abbiati, the
        Bishop of Bobbio who was born in Gorgonzola, donated a reproduction of the
        painting of the Sanctuary of Bobbio depicting Our Lady of Help, to which the little
        Sanctuary was later dedicated, due to popular devotion.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about Ca\' Busca -->
    <string name="ca_busca">Ca\' Busca</string>

    <!-- Text about about Ca\' Busca -->
    <string name="ca_busca_info">
        Ca\'busca, as Villa Serbelloni Busca Sola Cabiati is commonly called, was the country
        residence of the ancient and noble Serbelloni family from Milan.\nIt is composed
        of a main building, a system of rural courts, a sixteenth century tower, a covered
        wooden bridge that crosses the Naviglio della Martesana.\nIt was purchased by
        the municipality in the second half of the XX century.\nPart of it houses the
        headquartes of the public library, in part it was fractioned into
        private housing units.\nThe beautiful park of the Villa has become a much loved
        public garden.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about Serbelloni Hospital -->
    <string name="old_hospital">Ospedale Serbelloni</string>

    <!-- Text about Serbelloni Hospital -->
    <string name="old_hospital_info">
        In his last will in 1802, the Duke Gian Galeazzo Sebelloni assigned lands and
        funds in order to build a church and a hospital.\nHis daughter Maria Luigia
        began to build the hospital in 1848, also thanks to the donations of the
        Legato Pio Serbelloni and the Opera Pia Gagnola.\nIts execution was entrusted
        to the architect Giacomo Muraglia, who conceived an elegant structure with
        medical and hygienic standards which were very advanced in those days.\nIn 1975
        this historic building was judged no longer suitable for its functions and since
        then the hospital activity has taken place in a more modern structure.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about the main Church of Gorgonzola -->
    <string name="major_church">Chiesa Prepositurale SS MM Gervasio e Protaso</string>

    <!-- Text about the main Church of Gorgonzola -->
    <string name="major_church_info">
        This is the main Church of the town and it was built in substitution of an
        older one, which dated back to the X century.\nThe new Church was made according
        the last will of Gian Galeazzo Serbelloni by his daughter in 1806.\nIts construction
        was entrusted to architect Simone Cantoni, and completed in 1820 by Giacomo
        Muraglia who also build the bell tower.\nIt consists of an elegant and harmonious
        structure in neoclassic style.\nThe Serbelloni Mausoleum stands at one of its
        sides, the Naviglio flows on the other side.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about Palazzo Pirola -->
    <string name="palazzo_pirola_fregnaneschi">Palazzo Fregnaneschi &#8211; Pirola</string>

    <!-- Text about Palazzo Pirola -->
    <string name="palazzo_pirola_fregnaneschi_info">
        The villa, which stands parallel to the Naviglio was already mentioned as one
        of the properties of the Fregnaneschi family in 1722 in a land register.\nAs
        time went by it subsequently became property of other
        families.\nDuring the latest decades of the XX century the palace was fractioned
        into several housing units. It has been under tutelage since 2002.\nThe subsequent
        restoration work has given new glory to this building of neoclassical
        appearance,and has brought to light a few decorative elements reputed lost.\nThe
        ground floor is property of the municipality.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about Giardino Sola Cabiati -->
    <string name="public_park">Giardino Sola Cabiati</string>

    <!-- Text about  -->
    <string name="public_park_info">
        Public park Giardino Sola Cabiati\nVia del Parco\nFree access\nFrom April to September
        8:00 &#8211; 20:00\nFrom October to March 8:00 &#8211; 17:30\nMember del ReGiS - Rete dei Giardini Storici.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about Stadio Comunale Città di Gorgonzola -->
    <string name="stadium">Stadio Comunale Città di Gorgonzola</string>

    <!-- Text about Stadio Comunale Città di Gorgonzola -->
    <string name="stadium_info">
        The stadium houses the matches A.S.Erminio Giana, the main football team in town
        which plays in the LegaPro italian championship.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about Cinema -->
    <string name="cinema">Sala Argentia</string>

    <!-- Text about Cinema-->
    <string name="cinema_info">
        Sala Argentia\nCinema and Theatre\nVia Matteotti 30\nSummer break during July and August\nInfo on: http://www.argentia.it/
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about Sports Centre -->
    <string name="sports_centre">Sports Centre</string>

    <!-- Text about Sports Centre -->
    <string name="sports_centre_info">
        Sports Center Seven Infinity\nVia Toscana 7\nFitness\nTennis\nSPA &amp; wellness\nFootball/n
        Indoor pool\nSummer Lido\nInfo on: https://www.seveninfinity.it/
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about the  library -->
    <string name="public_library">Biblioteca civica \"Franco Galato\"</string>

    <!-- Text about the public library -->
    <string name="public_library_info">
        Public Library "Franco Galato"\nBelongs to CUBI, web of public libraries\nVia
        Montenero 30\nFree access:\nThursday and Saturday 9:30 &#8211; 12:30\nFrom
        Tuesday to Saturday 14:00 &#8211; 18:30\nStudying and reading newspaper and
        magazines:\nTuesday, Wednesday and Friday 9:30 &#8211; 12:30\nOnline search for
        available titles:\nhttp://www.cubinrete.it
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about events Palazzo Pirola -->
    <string name="events_pp">Palazzo Pirola</string>

    <!-- Text about events in Palazzo Pirola -->
    <string name="events_pp_info">
        Events and art exhibitions.\nInfo on: http://palazzopirola.it/
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about sagra gorgonzola -->
    <string name="sagra">Sagra Nazionale del Gorgonzola</string>

    <!-- Text about sagra gorgonzola -->
    <string name="sagra_info">
        Every year since 1998, around the third weekend of September there is a big party
        in town, the streets get populated by many people who come to celebrate the
        famous blue cheese in his hometown, from which it took its name.\nCrowded and
        cheerful, it\'s an end of Summer party full of events, stalls, good food, good
        wine and beer, but above all so much gorgonzola cheese.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about Saint Catherine Fair -->
    <string name="fair">Saint Catherine Fair</string>

    <!-- Text about Saint Catherine Fair -->
    <string name="fair_info">
        In 1785 a new fair was established, which became an important annual appointment
        in which agricultural goods and products, diary, court and working animals were
        bought and sold.\nSince then every year Saint Catherine Fair takes place on the
        weekend around the 25 November, the day dedicated to the Saint of Alexandria of
        Egypt.\nNowadays the agricultural element of the is much less pronounced,
        nonetheless it keeps being a very heartfelt, cheerful fair which marks the
        passage fromm deep Autumn to Winter.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about art market -->
    <string name="mercatino">Art and Culture market</string>

    <!-- Text about art market -->
    <string name="mercatino_info">
        Every month on the first Sunday, except in January and in August.\nVia and Piazza Italia, Via Cavour and Piazza San Francesco.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about art market -->
    <string name="car_directions">Car</string>

    <!-- Text about art market -->
    <string name="car_directions_info">
        From Milan and Bergamo with strada provinciale ex strada statale 11 Padana Superiore
        (SP EX SS 11) which connect Turin to Venice going through Milan and
        crossing the Po Valley.\nFrom Monza and Brianza and Melzo with
        strada provinciale SP 13.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about art market -->
    <string name="metro_directions">Metro</string>

    <!-- Text about art market -->
    <string name="metro_directions_info">
        In Gorgonzola there are three stops of the Milan &#8211; Gessate branch of
        Line M2, or green line, of the metro of Milan:\nVilla Pompea (Frazione Riva),
        Gorgonzola, Cascina Antonietta.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about art market -->
    <string name="bike_directions">Bike</string>

    <!-- Text about art market -->
    <string name="bike_directions_info">
        A bike path starting from Milan, in Via Melchiorre Gioia, to Cassano d\'Adda
        along the Naviglio della Martesana. From here it is possible to go as
        far as Lecco via the Ciclabile d\'Adda along the River Adda.\nA bike path from
        Gorgonzola to Melzo is under construction.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about art market -->
    <string name="bus_directions">Bus</string>

    <!-- Text about art market -->
    <string name="bus_directions_info">
        Bus Z403 to Melzo, from the Gorgonzola M2 metro station.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about art market -->
    <string name="train_directions">Train</string>

    <!-- Text about art market -->
    <string name="train_directions_info">
        Trains departing from the near town of Melzo to Milan and to Treviglio, and then
        from there to Bergamo, Brescia and Venice.
    </string>

</resources>
