<resources>

    <!-- Name of the app -->
    <string name="app_name">Gorgo Tour Guide</string>

    <!-- Name of the fragment dedicated to the general information about the town -->
    <string name="general_info_fragment">General Information</string>

    <!-- Name of the fragment dedicated to the things too see in town  -->
    <string name="places_to_see_fragment">Things to see</string>

    <!-- Name of the fragment dedicated to the things to do in town -->
    <string name="events_in_gorgonzola_fragment">Things to do</string>

    <!-- Name of the fragment dedicated to the directions to get to the town -->
    <string name="flora_of_naviglio_della_martesana_fragment">Directions</string>

    <!--  -->
    <!-- General text for the content decription of the images -->
    <string name="a_view_of_gorgonzola">a view of Gorgonzola</string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about basic info about the town -->
    <string name="gorgonzola">Gorgonzola</string>

    <!-- Text of the basic description about the town -->
    <string name="gorgonzola_description">
        Gorgonzola is a town in the Metropolitan City of Milan, in Lombardy.
        It has around 20500 inhabitants called \"gorgonzolesi\".\n\"Gorgonzoeula\"
        (IPA: [ɡurɡũˈdzøːla]) is the name of the town in the dialect spoken
        around Milan. Sometimes the town is aldo called by some
        \"GorgoTown\" in an affectionate and informal fashion.\nBesides the
        characteristic city centre, the territory of Gorgonzola includes the
        hamlets of Frazione Riva, Località Produttiva, Cascina Mugnaga,
        Cascina Vergani, Cascina Nuova e Cascina Antonietta.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about basic geographical info about the town -->
    <string name="geography">Geography</string>

    <!-- Text of the basic geographical description of the town -->
    <string name="geographical_info">
        Gorgonzola is located at 133 m above sea level, 13 Km North &#8211; East of Milan
        in the Martesana territory, once called Martesana county.\nThe Naviglio della
        Martesana, an artificial canal, and the torrent Molgora flow through its flat
        territory.\nThe Pre &#8211; Alps of Bergamo and Lecco and Valtellina are not
        faraway to the North.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about gorgonzola cheese -->
    <string name="cheese">Gorgonzola Cheese</string>

    <!-- Text about gorgonzola cheese -->
    <string name="gorgonzola_cheese_info">
        According to most Gorgonzola is the birthplace of the blue cheese and it
        had been the main centre of its production and trade for many centuries.\nOriginally
        called Stracchino di Gorgonzola, and then also Stracchino verde, gorgonzola cheese
        was produced with the Autumn milk of the weary (stracch in dialect) cows during
        the transhumance from the summer mountain pastures.\nGradually its production
        extended to an area ranging from Piedmont and Lombardy which is now defined and
        protected by the PDO mark and the Consorzio per la Tutela del Formaggio Gorgonzola DOP,
        which has also set the processing procedure to obtain the famous blue cheese.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about Parco Agricolo Sud Milano -->
    <string name="parco_agricolo">Parco Agricolo Sud Milano</string>

    <!-- Text about Parco Agricolo Sud Milano -->
    <string name="parco_agricolo_info">
        Gorgonzola is the most North &#821; Eastern town belonging to the Parco Agricolo
        Sud Milano, which includes the land of the towns and villages of the Southern
        half of the metropolitan belt surrounding Milan.\nHere agriculture is the
        main activity supporting the protection of the environment and the landscape,
        even if there are also untouched and protected areas, giving the park a high
        plant and animal biodiversity.\nTourism is of a rural and naturalistic kind.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about Gorgonzola in letterature -->
    <string name="literature_curiosity">Literature Curiosity</string>

    <!-- Text of the literature curiosity about Gorgonzola -->
    <string name="literature_curiosity_text">
        In The Bethrothed by Alessandro Manzoni, chapter XVI, it is told that Renzo,
        fleeing from Milan where he was involved in a riot and risked to be arrested,
        headed to Bergamo, in the Republic of Venice, and stopped for dinner in an inn
        in Gorgonzola.
    </string>

    <!-- Title of the Card about the twin towns of Gorgonzola -->
    <string name="twin_towns">Twin Towns</string>

    <!-- Text about the twin towns of Gorgonzola -->
    <string name="twin_towns_info">
        Ambert in Auvergne, France, since 2003.\nBoth cities are located almost at the
        same latitude, but most of all both are known for their own blue cow\'s milk cheese,
        Fourme d\'Ambert and Gorgonzola.\nAnnweiler am Trifels, Germany, since
        September 2008.\nAnnweiler is a town in the Südliche Weinstraße district,
        in Rhineland-Palatinate, Germany.
    </string>

</resources>
